{
    "questions": {
        "1": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "If an object is positively charged, theoretically the mass of the object _________",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "Increases slightly by a factor of 9.11*10-31 kg",
                "Decreases slightly by a factor of 9.11*10-31 kg",
                "Remains the same",
                "May increase or decrease"
            ]
        },
        "2": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Two equally charged spheres attract each other. Now if they touch each other then they will __________",
            "ans": "d",
            "options": [
                "Attract each other with the same amount of force",
                "Repel each other",
                "Attract each other with less amount of force",
                "Donâ€™t attract or repel"
            ]
        },
        "3": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Dr. Gilbert tried to hold a brass rod by hand and induce static electricity in it by friction. Why did he fail?",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "Static electricity is induced only on insulators while brass is conducting",
                "The induced static charge flew through his hand and body to the ground",
                "The static charge was not produced at all",
                "It is not possible to induce static electricity by friction"

            ]
        },
        "4": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "The band gap between the valence band and conduction band is the measure of ______",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "The conductivity of the material",
                 "The resistivity of the material",
                 "Charge density",
                 "Ease of ionization"
            ]
        },
        "5": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Insulation breakdown may occur at _______",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "High temperature",
                "Low temperature",
                "At any temperature",
                "Depends on pressure"
            ]
        },
        "6": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Which group among the following is insulator?",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "Silver, copper, gold",
                "Paper, glass, cotton",
                "The human body, wood, iron",
                "Glass, copper, paper"
            ]
        },
        "7": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What will be the total charge on the aluminum rod, if the aluminum rod is charged by the plastic rod through electrostatic induction?",
            "ans": "c",
            "options": [
                "positive",
                "negative",
                "zero",
                "dual"
            ]
        },
        "8": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Why a person standing inside a Faraday cage do not get affected by the electric field?",
            "ans": "d",
            "options": [
                "Since the electric potential is positive",
                "Since the electric potential is negative",
                "Since the electric potential is zero",
                "Since the outside electric field gets cancelled by the inside electric field"
            ]
        },
        "9": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What is the behaviour of like charges?",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "attract",
                "repel",
                "exchange charges",
                "no changes"
            ]
        },
        "10": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Coulomb law is usually applied in the area of ",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "Electromagnetics",
                "Electrostatics",
                "Magnetism",
                "Gravitation"
            ]
        },
        "11": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What is the unit used for measuring electric charge?",
            "ans": "d",
            "options": [
                "Ampere",
                "Farad",
                "Volt",
                "Coulomb"
            ]
        },
        "12": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Coulomb law is applicable only for",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "Point charges at rest",
                "Inverse square law is not satisfied",
                "Charges are in arbitrary shape",
                "Calculate the charge on big planets"
            ]
        },
        "13": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "A point charge Q is far from all other charges. At a distance of 2 m from Q, the electric field is 20 N/C. What is the force a charge of 5 Coulombs feels?",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "4 N",
                "100 N",
                "40 N",
                "10 N"
            ]
        },
        "14": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What is the magnitude of the electric field intensity at a point where a proton experiences an electrostatic force of magnitude 2.30 x 10-25 newton?",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "1.44 x 10-6 N/C",
                "3.68 x 106 N/C",
                "1.44 x 1044 N/C",
                "3.68 x 10-44 N/C"
            ]
        },
        "15": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What is the formula for electric field ",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "E=F/D ",
                "W= F*D ",
                "V= D/t ",
                "I= V/R"
            ]
        },
        "16": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Which statement is true? i. E= F/D, ii. E= kq/r^2",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "the first one is electric field formula ",
                "the second one is the electric field formula ",
                "Both are electric field formula ",
                "None of them are electric field formula"
            ]
        },
        "17": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What is the surface charge density when the hollow spherical conductor of radius is 3m with a charge of +20uC?",
            "ans": "b",
            "options": [
                "1.789x10^-7 c/m2",
                "1.768x10^-7c/m2",
                "1.769x10^7 c/m2",
                "1.788x10^7 c/m2"
            ]
        },
        "18": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "Two conducting spheres of radius r1 = 8 cm and r2 = 2 cm are separated by a distance much larger than 8 cm and are connected by a thin conducting wire. A total charge of Q = +100 nC is placed on one of the spheres. After a fraction of a second, the charge Q is redistributed and both the spheres attain electrostatic equilibrium. Calculate the charge and surface charge density on each sphere.",
            "ans": "d",
            "options": [
                "0.99 x 10^-6 Cm^-2 and 3.6 x 10^-6 Cm^-2",
                "0.99 x 10^-6 Cm^-2 and 3.7 x 10^-6 Cm^-2",
                "0.99 x 10^-6 Cm^-2 and 3.8 x 10^-6 Cm^-2",
                "0.99 x 10^-6 Cm^-2 and 3.9 x 10^-6 Cm^-2"
            ]
        },
        "19": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "A spherical conductor with radius 40cm has a surface charge density of +20 uC/m^2. What is the total charge on this sphere?",
            "ans": "c",
            "options": [
                "3.04 x 10^-5 C",
                "4.07 x 10^-5 C",
                "4.02 x 10^-5 C",
                "3.02 x 10^-5 C"
            ]
        },
        "20": {
            "type": 1,
            "question": "What is the electric flux through a sphere of radius 4m that contains a +50 uC at its center?",
            "ans": "a",
            "options": [
                "5.65 x 10^6 Nm^2/C",
                "5.66 x 10^6 Nm^2/C",
                "5.67 x 10^6 Nm^2/C",
                "5.68x 10^6 Nm^2/C"
            ]
        }
    }
}